Kevin Dang

56 Marbleseed Cres, Brampton, ON L6R 2J8 437-477-3946

http://www.kevindang12.com/kevin-website dankevin@my.yorku.ca

Hiring Manager

RE: Software Developer

Dear Hiring Manager,

I am writing to inquire about the co-op placement as a Software Developer. My enthusiasm for constantly learning the latest technologies has inspired me to design, build, and deploy many software side projects in my personal time. A portfolio website that I built using React is viewable here, and it features all my various side/passion software projects.

My experience includes working as a Junior Programmer co-op at the Screen Industries Research and Training Centre, where I worked on a Unity mobile app that utilized a Muse headband to record brain activity in response to visual stimuli. Additionally, as a Software Engineer co-op at Healthcare Systems R&A, I contributed to a Brain-Computer Interface project designed to help stroke patients interact with mini-games. Through these roles, I have worked with stakeholders, product managers, and my scrum team and researched and pushed for solutions to solve our problems (such as which open-source libraries to use).

I am currently a Computer Science student at York University (Transfer Student) with a GPA of 3.9/4.0, and a graduate of Sheridan College with a GPA of 3.86/4.0.

I welcome the opportunity to speak with you about the Software Developer position. I believe that my previous work experience and drive to constantly learn new skills make me a good fit for the role.

Thank you for your time,

Kevin Dang

Kevin Dang

56 Marbleseed Cres, Brampton, ON, L6R 2J8 437-477-3946

http://www.kevindang12.com/kevin-website | dankevin@my.yorku.ca https://github.com/KevinDang12

Work Experience

Junior Programmer (Co-op)

Screen Industries Research and Training Centre

January 2024 - April 2024

- Helped develop a mobile app to capture the user's response time when presented with a stimulus using the Unity Game Engine and C#; optimized the program to reduce the lag by ~30% and wrote technical documentation detailing the Unity components
- Developed a Unity plugin using C++ to generate character animation using an Al-powered audio prompt

Software Engineer (Co-op)

Healthcare Systems R&A

May 2023 - July 2023

- Contributed to a Brain-Computer Interface Machine Learning AI model for Stroke Rehabilitation;
 developed a mini-game using Python to allow patients to interact with the game using motor imagery
- As a team lead, I researched and recommended management as to which open-source libraries to use to help implement a data-cleaning method to process and improve data quality by ~20% for the ML model

Teaching Assistant

Sheridan College

September 2022 - December 2022

- TA'd in Java Object-Oriented Programming, Computer Math, and Web development courses
- Collaborated with my co-workers in updating the official Sheridan College website; obtained requirements from stakeholders to implement new time management functionality using HTML and CSS

Technical Skills

- Proficient in technologies such as Python, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, RESTful APIs, Docker; knowledge of SQL, and database management systems, as well as AWS
- Knowledge of Agile methodology, unit testing, and using version control technologies (Git, GitHub) in a professional environment
- Experience in Object-Oriented Programming, as well as using Windows and Unix command-line interfaces

Education

Bachelor of Science (Honours), Computer Science (Transfer Student) York University 2024 - Present

Advanced Diploma, Computer Engineering Technology Sheridan College

2020 - 2024

Side Projects

Steam Review Summarizer

- A Steam Review Summarizer React web app that summarizes reviews for Steam games using the Steam API and OpenAI GPT-3.5 model, it is accessible through a website hosted on Firebase here
- It includes a backend server built using Node.js with the open-source Express framework and uses RESTful APIs for server-client communication

Notepad App

- An Android Notepad app with third-party Google user authentication using OAuth 2.0; video demonstration can be found here
- The notepad app is cross-platform and uses a cloud backend and RESTful API to sync to a <u>Windows</u> desktop app and a React web app hosted on Amazon Web Services here